<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Civ4GameText>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_DOTO</Tag>
		<English>[H1][BOLD]*** Doto Features ***[\BOLD][\H1]
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Ranged Immunity[\BOLD][NEWLINE]no more suicidal ranged units.
siege land units will be able to inflict one time damage without the risk of being hit back by the defender.
the damage will be a percentage up to the combat limit (each unit has one).
hit and/or damage can be randomized.
if the defender is also a siege unit, it will attack back e.g. -> retaliate.
[NEWLINE]
key features:
[ICON_BULLET] each ranged attack has a number of free ranged attacks (3 default).
[ICON_BULLET] each unit has a cool down of 2 (default).
[ICON_BULLET] after a unit attack the max attack rounds - 3/3, 
[NEWLINE] the count down of the cooldown will start its count per turn. when CD is done,
the unit attack count will reset
[ICON_BULLET] if a unit wont attack at its turn -> the attack count will be reduced.
[ICON_BULLET] on the third attack, a precentage of damage will be dealt to the attacker.
[NEWLINE][BOLD] Game options: [\BOLD]
[ICON_BULLET] Raned immunity
[ICON_BULLET] Random Hit -> not every hit is succesful
[ICON_BULLET] Random Damage -> not evey Damage dealt is the same
[ICON_BULLET] Ranged Retaliate -> if the defender is a siege ranged immunity unit ->
unlike regular unit, it will strike back the siege ranged attacker.
[ICON_BULLET] AI code was added , seems that ai use it well.

this is based off VIP mod and inspired by civ4 Reimagined.

[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Governor[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
The governor is a unit that is spawned when a city is created.
in addition to the unit, it will generate a greate people specialist in the city.
this is to represent the city perks it will get from the unit map promotions.
the position of this governor specialist is located at the right left view in the city.
[ICON_BULLET] the unit cannot be moved or do any action but skip or fortify.
[ICON_BULLET] the governor will get xp from 2 parts:
					[NEWLINE] city growth in size (fixed incremental growth steps) for example on size 3 it will get 1 xp point
					[NEWLINE] Cottages / Towns etc give the city 1 xp score per turn if the city works the tiles they are on.
					the score is accumilated for the governor unit to a special threshold.
					once it is reached, the governor will get xp.
					this can happen up to 10 times -> 10 xp points in total.
					the more cottegaes , the faster the xp will be given.
[ICON_BULLET] once the unit will get a xp level up, it willbe able to choose to promote to a specific governor promotion tree. these promotions are city perks improvements.
and will be reflected on the freat person icon of the governor.
[ICON_BULLET] the governor will not get any other perks given to all specialist via civics and such.

[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]City States[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Unique to Doto, City states are similar to CIVV+.
the cities will abide to several key rules. a player can have special unique trade agreement with each city to receive unique city perks along with a unique resource.
City states can be tweaked and changed in the GlobalDefinesAlt.xml at the bottom of it.
there are explanations per parameter.

- city states will be randomly spawned at turn 1 (only Ancient era).
- cannot grow beyond culture defined limit (parameter).
- cannot grow under defined culture limit (parameter).
- i conjured method to color the inner culture borders to distinct cs area controlled.
- new free trade agreement with CS -> will provide both the CS and the trading civ a Unique Bonus commerce (displayed in the cs Trait info).
- cs cannot build wonders.
- cannot be vassal.
- ai will always raze cs and vice versa (haven't done code for human player , yet).
- new population system - cities beyond parameter defined size will begin getting special specialists named civilians instead of population.
dynamically - there are 3 types, 1 per yield that is given to the city according to its lowest yield output.
these consume food.
there are several parameters - can be turned off as a game option in the GlobalDefinesAlt.xml.
- cannot trade cs in city trade...
- cs build units without Bonus Prereq! (i think i made it also a parameter).
- cs gets a tech diffusion and an enhanced one as well -> is not regular tech diffusion dependent!.
- cs scoring is based off of population and land -> with power ups to compensate for one city....
- cannot build settlers....
- have a unique resource to trade with other civs - provide 1 health or happy (2 per city state)
- amount of cs is adjustable according to world size.
- cs can be random or be chosen in the custom game mode (make sure to define it in the parameter in GlobalDefinesAlt.xml!).
- city states leaders are less inclined for wars, lower attitude thresholds and will not chase war related victory.
- there are 8 city states
- city states unique units are a duplicate of existing similar civs.
- cs palace is unique with some more perks ups.
- cs cannot found religions.
- cs cannot found corporations.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Civic Dependency[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
New Unique Government Civic system.
each gov civic has 2 dependent civic options with each has 2 civics to choose from.
on any given time, dependent civics can only be chosen by the parent government civic.
new AI logic New civic screen.
reworked all civics.
new civic tags with new features.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Unit Blockade[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Enemy units block direction of 45 degrees . meaning the player must confront and attack, or go around in a longer path.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Influence Driven war[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
winning battle and/or pillaging can change the target tile culture in the player favor.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Mountains Back to service[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Units can walk over mountains (not all units).
also bonuses can appear on peaks.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Forbidden Religion[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
each civ has one religion it cannot found nor it can convert to.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Limited Religion[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Each civ can only found a limited number of religions.
default is 1 per civ. later on ill make it that some civs can found more.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Culture Control and Improvement Limits[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Forts now spread culture around them.
Some improvements cannot be built near each other.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Cultural Golden Age[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
after a certain threshold , from Culture, a golden Age will be triggered.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Wonder Limit (along with Wonder build 1:1 obsoleet)[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
each city can build wonders limited by its culture size.
if combined with wonder obsolete game options -> if a city has an obsolete wonder which is included in the wonder count,
it will ignore it and open a new wonder slot -> meaning for example culture limit is 5, city has 5 wonders which 1 is obsolete -> the option will allow the construction of the 6th
wonder in that case.

[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Improvement Decay:[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Improvements will dimish to none is not worked for a set number of turns.
its a game option.


[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Tech Obsolete Improvement:[\BOLD][NEWLINE]
Improvements will go obsolete with a specific tech. i did not implement this.
its a code i created for Chrinicles of Mankind by Nexus.
its a game option.

</English>
		</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
